Now when Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea, in the days of King Herod. Behold, wise
men from the east came to Jerusalem. Saying, Where is He who is born King of the Jews?
For we saw His star in the east and have come to worship Him.
When King Herod heard it, he was troubled. And all Jerusalem with him. Gathering
together all the chief priests and scribes of the people. He asked them where the
Christ would be born. They
said to him: In Bethlehem of Judea, for thus it is written through the prophet. You,
Bethlehem, land of Judah, are in no way least among the princes of Judah. For
out of you shall come forth a governor who shall shepherd My people Israel. Then
Herod secretly called the wise men. And learned from them exactly what time the star
appeared. He
sent them to Bethlehem and said: Go and search diligently for the young child. When
you have found him, bring me word, so that I also may come and worship him. They,
having heard the King, went their way. And behold, the star which they saw in the east
went before them. Until it came and stood over where the young child was. When
they saw the star, they rejoiced with exceedingly great joy. They
came into the house and saw the young child with Mary, his mother. And they fell down and
worshiped him. Opening
their treasures, they offered to him gifts: gold, frankincense, and myrrh. Being
warned in a dream not to return to Herod. They went back to their own country another
way. Now when
they had departed, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared to Joseph in a dream. Saying, Arise
and take the young child and his mother. And flee into Egypt and stay there until I
tell you. For Herod will seek the young child to destroy him. He arose
and took the young child and his mother by night. And departed into Egypt. And was there
until the death of Herod. That it might be fulfilled which was spoken by the Lord through
the prophet. Out of Egypt I called My Son. Then Herod, when
he saw that he was mocked by the wise men, was exceedingly angry. And sent out and
killed all the male children who were in Bethlehem. And in all the surrounding countryside, from two years
old and under. According to the exact time which he had learned from the wise men.
Then that which was
spoken by Jeremiah the prophet was fulfilled. Saying, A voice was heard in Rama, lamentation,
weeping, and great mourning. Rachel weeping for her children, and she would not
be comforted. Because they are no more. But when
Herod was dead, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared in a dream to Joseph in Egypt.
Saying, Arise and take the young child and his mother. And go into the land of Israel.
For those who sought the young child's life are dead.
He arose and took the young child and his mother. And came into the land of Israel.
But when he heard that Archelaus was reigning over Judea in the place of his father Herod.
He was afraid to go there.
Being warned in a dream, he withdrew into the region of Galilee. And came and lived in
a city called Nazareth. That it might be fulfilled which was spoken through the prophets.
- He will be called a Nazarene!